In this and the next few
在这一段和下一段视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
videos, I want to tell
我想向你介绍一种
you about a machine learning application
机器学习的应用实例
example, or a machine
或者说是
learning application history centered
机器学习在一种叫
around an application called Photo OCR  .
照片OCR技术中的应用历史
There are three reasons
我想介绍这部分内容的原因
why I want to do this,
主要有以下三个
first I wanted to show you an
第一 我想向你展示
example of how a complex
一个复杂的机器学习系统
machine learning system can be put together.
是如何被组合起来的
Second, once told the concepts of
第二 我想介绍一下
a machine learning a type line
机器学习流水线（machine learning pipeline）的有关概念
and how to allocate resources when
以及如何分配资源
you're trying to decide what to do next.
来对下一步计划作出决定
And this can either be in
这既包括你需要自己
the context of you working
开发一个很复杂的
by yourself on the big
机器学习应用的情况
application Or it can
也可能适用于
be the context of a team
一个开发团队
of developers trying to build
希望共同建立一个复杂的
a complex application together.
机器学习应用的情况
And then finally, the Photo
最后
OCR problem also gives
我也想通过介绍照片OCR问题
me an excuse to tell you
的机会来告诉你
about just a couple more interesting
机器学习的诸多
ideas for machine learning.
有意思的想法和理念
One is some ideas of
其中之一是如何将机器学习
how to apply machine learning to
应用到计算机视觉问题中
computer vision problems, and second
第二是有关
is the idea of artificial data
人工数据合成（artificial data synthesis）的概念
synthesis, which we'll see in a couple of videos.
我们将在接下来的几段视频中进行介绍
So, let's start by talking about what is the Photo OCR problem.
好的 那么我们就从介绍什么是照片OCR问题开始
Photo OCR stands for
照片OCR表示
Photo Optical Character Recognition.
照片光学字符识别（photo optical character recognition）
With the growth of digital photography
随着数码摄影的日益流行
and more recently the growth of
已经近年来手机中
camera in our cell phones
拍照功能的逐渐成熟
we now have tons of visual
我们现在很容易就会有
pictures that we take all over the place.
一大堆从各地拍摄的数码照片
And one of the things that
吸引众多开发人员的
has interested many developers is
其中一个应用是
how to get our computers to
如何让计算机更好地理解
understand the content of these pictures a little bit better.
这些照片的背景环境
The photo OCR problem focuses
这种照片OCR技术
on how to get computers to
主要解决的问题是让计算机
read the text to the purest in images that we take.
从我们拍摄的照片中读出文字的信息
Given an image like this it
用这样一张照片举例说明
might be nice if a computer
如果计算机能够读出
can read the text in this
照片中的文字就太好了
image so that if you're
这样一来如果你
trying to look for this
下次想再把这张照片找出来时
picture again you type in
你就输入照片中的文字
the words, lulu bees and
LULA B'S
and have it automatically pull
然后计算机就自动地
up this picture, so that
找出这张照片来
you're not spending lots of
这样你就不用花几个小时
time digging through your photo
把你的相片集翻个底朝天
collection Maybe hundreds of
从几百上千张照片中
thousands of pictures in.
把这张找出来
The Photo OCR problem
照片OCR就是解决这一问题的
does exactly this, and it does so in several steps.
它有如下几个步骤
First, given the picture it
首先 给定某张图片
has to look through the image
它将把图像浏览一遍
and detect where there is text in the picture.
然后找出这张图片中哪里有文字信息
And after it has done
在完成这一步以后
that or if it successfully does
成功找出有文字的位置以后
that it then has to
接下来要做的就是
look at these text regions and
重点关注这些文字区域
actually read the text in
并且在这些区域中
those regions, and hopefully if
对文字内容进行识别
it reads it correctly, it'll come
如果能正确读出的话
up with these transcriptions of
它会将这些内容进行转录
what is the text that appears in the image.
记录下图片中出现的这些文本
Whereas OCR, or optical
虽然现在OCR
character recognition of scanned
或者说光学文字识别
documents is relatively easier
对扫描的文档来说已经是一个
problem, doing OCR from
比较简单的问题了
photographs today is still a
但对于数码照片来说
very difficult machine learning problem,
现在还是一个比较困难的机器学习问题
and you can do this.
研究这个目的
Not only can this help
不仅仅是因为
our computers to understand the
这可以让计算机
content of our though
通过拍摄的数码相片
images better, there are
更好地理解我们所处的环境
also applications like helping blind
更重要的是 它衍生了很多应用
people, for example, if you
比如在帮助盲人方面
could provide to a blind person
假如你能为盲人提供一种照相机
a camera that can look
这种相机可以“看见”
at what's in front of
他们前面有什么东西
them, and just tell them the
可以告诉他们
words that my be on
面前的路牌上
the street sign in front of them.
写的是什么字
With car navigation systems.
现在也有研究人员将照片OCR技术应用到汽车导航系统中
For example, imagine if your
想象一下你的车
car could read the street
能读出街道的标识
signs and help you navigate to your destination.
并且将你导航至目的地
In order to perform photo OCR, here's what we can do.
要实现照片OCR 我们可以这样做
First we can go through the
首先我们可以通览图像
image and find the regions where there's text and image.
并找出有文字的图像区域
So, shown here is
这里展示的例子就是
one example of text and
照片OCR系统可能会识别到的
image that the photo OCR system may find.
图像中的文字信息
Second, given the rectangle around
第二 通过得到的文字区域的
that text region, we can
矩形轮廓
then do character segmentation, where
我们可以进行字符切分
we might take this text box
比如对这个文字框
that says "Antique Mall" and
我们或许能认出“ANTIQUE MALL”
try to segment it out
然后我们会试着将其
into the locations of the individual characters.
分割成独立的字符
And finally, having segmented out
最后 在成功将字段分割为
into individual characters, we can
独立的字符后
then run a crossfire, which
我们可以运行一个分类器
looks at the images of the
输入这些可识别的字符
visual characters, and tries to
然后试着识别出
figure out the first character's an
第一个字母是一个A
A, the second character's an
第二个字母是一个N
N, the third character is
第三个字母是一个T
a T, and so on,
等等
so that up by doing all
因此通过完成所有这些工作
this how that hopefully you can then
按理说你就能识别出
figure out that this phrase
这个字段写的是
is Rulegee's antique mall
LULAB'S ANTIQUE MALL
and similarly for some of
然后图片中其他有文字的地方
the other words that appear in that image.
也是类似的方法进行处理
I should say that there are some photo OCR systems
实际上有很多照片OCR系统
that do even more complex things,
会进行更为复杂的处理
like a bit of spelling correction at the end.
比如在最后会进行拼写校正
So if, for example, your
所以比如说
character segmentation and character
假如你的字符分割
classification system tells you
和分类系统告诉你
that it sees the
它识别到的字是
word c 1 e a
“C 1 E A N I N G”
n i n g. Then,
那么
you know, a sort of spelling
很多拼写修正系统
correction system might tell
会告诉你
you that this is probably the
这可能是单词
word 'cleaning', and your
“cleaning”的拼写
character classification algorithm had
你的字符分类算法
just mistaken the l for a 1.
刚才把字母 l 识别成了数字 1
But for the purpose of what
但在这节课中
we want to do in
我们要做的事情
this video, let's ignore this last
会不考虑最后这一步
step and just focus on the
只关注前面三个步骤
system that does these three
也就是文字检测
steps of text detection, character
字符分割
segmentation, and character classification.
以及字符分类
A system like this is
那么像这样的一个系统
what we call a machine learning pipeline.
我们把它称之为机器学习流水线（machine learning pipeline）
In particular, here's a picture
具体来说 这幅图表示的
showing the photo OCR pipeline.
就是照片OCR的流水线
We have an image, which then
我们有一幅图像
fed to the text detection system
然后传给文字检测系统
text regions, we then segment
识别出文字以后
out the characters--the individual characters in
我们将字段分割为独立的字符
the text--and then finally we recognize the individual characters.
最后我们队单个的字母进行识别
In many complex machine learning
在很多复杂的机器学习系统中
systems, these sorts of
这种流水线形式
pipelines are common, where you
都非常普遍
can have multiple modules--in this
在流水线中会有多个不同的模块
example, the text detection, character
比如在本例中
segmentation, character recognition modules--each of
我们有文字检测 字符分割和字母识别
which may be machine learning component,
其中每个模块都可能是一个机器学习组件
or sometimes it may not
或者有时候
be a machine learning component but
这些模块也不一定是机器学习组件
to have a set of modules
只是一个接一个
that act one after another on
连在一起的
some piece of data in order
一系列数据
to produce the output you want,
最终得出你希望的结果
which in the photo OCR example
在照片OCR例子中
is to find the
就是最终识别到的
transcription of the text that appeared in the image.
图片中的文字信息
If you're designing a machine learning
如果你要设计一个机器学习系统
system one of the
其中你需要作出的
most important decisions will often
最重要的决定
be what exactly is the pipeline that you want to put together.
就是你要怎样组织好这个流水线
In other words, given the photo
换句话说
OCR problem, how do you
在这个照片OCR问题中
break this problem down into
你应该如何将这个问题分成
a sequence of different modules.
一系列不同的模块
And you design the pipeline
你需要设计这个流程
and each the performance of each of the modules in your pipeline.
以及你的流水线中的每一个模块
will often have a big
这通常会影响到你
impact on the final performance of your algorithm.
最终的算法的表现
If you have a team of
如果你有一个工程师的团队
engineers working on a
在完成同样类似的任务
problem like this is also very
那么通常你可以让
common to have different
不同的人来完成
individuals work on different modules.
不同的模块
So I could easily imagine tech
所以我可以假设
easily being the of anywhere
文字检测这个模块
from 1 to 5 engineers,
需要大概1到5个人
character segmentation maybe another
字符分割部分
1-5 engineers, and character
需要另外1到5个人
recognition being another 1-5
字母识别部分
engineers, and so having a
还需要另外1到5个人
pipeline like often offers a
因此 使用流水线的方式
natural way to divide up
通常提供了一个很好的办法
the workload amongst different members of an engineering team, as well.
来将整个工作分给不同的组员去完成
Although, or course, all of
当然 所有这些工作
this work could also be done
都可以由一个人来完成
by just one person if that's how you want to do it.
如果一个人也能胜任的话
In complex machine learning systems
在复杂的机器学习系统中
the idea of a pipeline, of
流水线的概念
a machine of a pipeline, is pretty pervasive.
已经渗透到各种应用中
And what you just saw is
你刚才看到的
a specific example of how
只是一种照片OCR
a Photo OCR pipeline might work.
流水线的运作过程
In the next few videos I'll
在接下来的几段视频中
tell you a little bit more
我还将继续向你介绍
about this pipeline, and we'll continue
更多的一些关于流水线的内容
to use this as an example
我们还将使用这个例子
to illustrate--I think--a few more
来展示机器学习中其他一些
key concepts of machine learning.
非常重要的概念